# Matthew Kaus

matthewkausfox@gmail.com | 505-879-6014| linkedIn/matthewpkaus | github/MatthewKaus | Portfolio

# SUMMARY

Web developer with data science experience educated at the University of New Mexico. Recently earned a certificate in full-stack web development from the University of Arizona, with knowledge in JavaScript, CSS, and ReactJS. Excited to develop responsive and dynamic websites, with a clean and modern user experience.

# **SKILLS**

Proficient in: JavaScript, Git, ReactJS, jQuery, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Heroku, MySQL, MongoDB

Familiar with, and interested in learning more about: Python, C++, Svelte, Angular JS, Vue.js, AWS

Tools: Git, LTFX, Slack, Zoom, GitHub

# **EDUCATION**

# **Full Stack Web Development**

Tuscon, AR | Aug 2021

UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA

After studying in college, I decided to take on the challenge and attend a coding boot-camp. Subjects studied included: MERN and SERN stack.

Liberal Arts Gallup, NM | Dec, 2020

University of New Mexico

With my enrollment in a dual credit high school, I was able to attend college to pursue my liberal arts. Given the opportunity to be part of the National Security Studies Program at UNM, stimulated my interest in computer science.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# TRILOGY EDUCATION | FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT (TA)

Remote | Apr 2021 - Present

- As a Teachers Assistant, during office hours I help students debug assignments and projects, and encourage them as they are working through a Full Stack Coding Curriculum.
- Assist students with online learning using tools including Zoom, Google Docs, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, and Git Bash.

## **WALMART** | REMODEL (TEMPORARY)

Gallup, NM | Apr 2022 - June 2022

- Built relationships with customers to increase likelihood of repeat business.
- Self-sufficient and can work alone without being supervised.
- Appreciates problem-solving in group environments.

### **UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO | RESEARCH**

Albuquerque, NM | Feb 2020 - May 2020

- Studied and utilized statistics, ATFX, R Programming within a three month span for Data Science.
- Presented technical research during conferences.

# PROJECTS

#### 

Stock Watchlist is a small application that allows users to look up a stock to find out the price, as well as the latest news.

- Utilizes Svelte as the framework of choice for learning new technology and methods of writing code.
- Time management of researching and testing code.

#### BENEFACTOR 2

HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, CSS3, MySQL, HANDLEBARS, EXPRESSJS

Benefactor is a gift giving service, that allows users to gift to friends, family, or to make a strangers day. Allowing users to make and share lists for future giving plans.

- Created the wire frame as well as creative lead for the user interface.
- Outlined the database and requirements for the model lead.

# MAKE ME! ☑

HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, CSS3, BULMA

Make Me Is a small application made to display a unique profile through a series of prompts.

- Established wire frame as well as user interface.
- Created communication channel using Discord.